A Guide to the Letters and Papers of William M. Connor 1908-1949
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Letters and Papers of Colonel William M. Connor 1908-1949
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
3287-a
This collection consists of ca. 118 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the William M. Connor Papers was a gift from Colonel William M. Connor, Jr., on 28 June, 1954.
Scope and Content Information
This addition to the William M. Connor Papers, 1909-1921, consists of ca. 21 items including correspondence, miscellaneous papers, and printed material concerning elections and finances in Cuba during the economic and electoral crisis of 1919-1920.
The correspondence, 1921, consists of General Enoch H. Crowder's carbons of his reports to the Secretary of State. The miscellaneous papers are arranged by subject and are placed chronologically. They are followed by the printed material which is also arranged by topic and filed chronologically.
Of particular interest in this material are the papers concerning electoral procedures, 1920, and the sugar situation, 1920-1921; the drafts of a bill, 1921 January through February, by Senator Cosme de Torriente concerning the liquidation of the moratorium to relieve Cuba's finances; the drafts of Rules concerning elections, 1921; and the summary, n.d., or General Gomez's statement about the Liberal Party's and the Democratic Party's positions on the elections.
Contents List
- Gen. Enoch H. Crowder to the Secretary of State re: the electoral situation 1921 Jan. 17, 2 TL (carbon)
- Memorandum to Maj. Connor re: a cable to the Secretary of State, concerning the Torriente Bill 1921 Jan. 20, TL
- [Gen. Crowder?] to Dr. Alfred Zayas, Havana 1921 Feb. 9, TL (carbon)
- Report and draft, in the form of a letter, Maj. Gen. Enoch H. Crowder to Norman H. Davis, Acting Sec. of State re: the political and financial crisis in Cuba 1921 March 12, ca. 3 items
- Draft of a cablegram for the Secretary of State re: grievances of the Liberal Party [1921?] March 14, 2 TL (carbons)
- Papers re: Electoral procedures in Cuba including a letter, 1920 Jan. 20 (carbon) to the President of the Republic re: electoral procedures 1920, ca. 8 items
- Papers re: the sugar situation in Cuba 1920-1921, ca. 25 items
- Papers and notes re: Quorums for Joint Session of Congress pusuant to Article 58 of the Cuban Constitution [ca. 1920?], ca. 14 items
- Statement of General Crowder re: the failure of Electoral Boards and Courts to function 1921 Jan. 13, 2 items
- Copy of a Bill re: suspension of payments and liquidation of credit companies, banks of issue and discounts and merchantile partnerships, and an amendment 1921 Jan., 3 items
- Drafts of a Bill by Senator Cosme de Torriente re: the liquidation of the moratorium (to relieve Cuba's finances) and papers re: the Bill 1921 Jan-Feb, ca. 28 items
- Copy of general instructions No. 49, Series A, issued by the Central Electoral Board 1921 Feb. 5, 1 item (carbon)
- Copy of the Charter of the Reserve Bank of Cuba, with suggestions for revision 1921, 1 item (carbon)
- Drafts of Rules re: elections; Translation of Act No. 227 re: elections; and typescripts of an exhortation for the Cubans to vote 1921, ca. 7 items
- Public Statement re: reorganization of certain banks n.d., TMs (carbon)
- Blank form for Santa Clara Province re: absence of elections in the various colleges n.d., 1 item
- Summary of Gen. Gomez's statement re: the Liberal Party position re: the elections, and of the Executive Committee of the Democratic Party's statement re: the elections n.d., 1 item (carbon)
- Printed report of the Secretaria de Agriculture, Comercio Y Trabajo, Decreto No. 1,123 1909 Dec. 25, 1 item
- Printed Materials: Garceta Official de la Republica de Cuba, Edicion Extraordinaria nos. 1-3, 9, 10, 14 1921, 6 items
- Newpaper Clippings re: Cuban elections 1921, 8 items
- Printed Materials: Certifico and Instruccion General of Dr. Narciso Davalos, Secretario de la Junta Central Electoral [1912?], 1 item